

+64 27 535 7874
manish_shah@me.com
Linkedin • Instagram • Facebook

Design & me

Clear thinking, strategic approach & e2e solutions are few things that make my everyday exciting.

As a design expert, I've had 10+ years of industry experience, working on a broad spectrum of projects, ranging from products to services, across various touchpoints and platforms.

I strive to design innovative, intuitive & optimised experiences for effective & enjoyable use, from conceptualisation to research/testing to implementation.

I'm always curious about new technologies, design processes & strategies that help me stay aware of the endless possibilities on my playground while getting a constant dose of inspiration.

Education

Master's In Strategic Design

Politechnico di Milano - Italy Sep-Dec, 2008

I was offered a fully sponsored scholarship by the Italian Institute of foreign trade — DIMI, at Politecnico di Milano, Italy. Master's In Design, Visual Communication

IDC, IIT Bombay - India 2006 - 2008

BFA, Applied Arts

Abhinav Kala Mahavidyalaya, Pune - India 2001 - 2006

Vocational Course, Photography

Fergusson College, Pune - India 2005 - 2006

Strengths

Product strategy Design strategy Problem-solving Documentation Innovation Facilitation Conducting tests Coding - HTML, CSS Wireframing User Experience User surveys App development - Swift Interaction design Prototyping Managing / Mentoring Visual design

Experience



Watercare Services Limited

Senior UX Strategist – Contract May 2021 - Present



PlaceMakers

Lead UX Designer Feb 2020 - Apr 2021 (1.3 years) In my recent role as UX Design Lead at Placemakers, my goal is to build an in-house design team to improve the experiences and create a vision for future digital products. Additionally, I'm also aiming to influence design thinking maturity within the organisation. I have been responsible for delivering an e2e customer-driven product experience across an app and web portal that met the trade customer needs achieving higher adoption, sales and usage for the digital channels.



Datacom

Lead UX Strategist – Contract Oct 2019 - Feb 2020 (4 months) I was leading a project defining and validating Datacom's new information architecture for their website. The overall customer goal was to make the content accessible and logical to discover. Catering, both familiar & unfamiliar type of customers, our ultimate aim was to achieve two business goals "New acquisition" and "Sustain & Grow". Followed by designing website templates defining the content hierarchy and structure.



Air New Zealand

Senior UX Strategist – Contract Jul 2019 - Oct 2019 (3 months) As a UX Strategist, I'm responsible for influencing product teams to create and deliver user-centric roadmaps. The primary phase of my role is to help conceptualise, define, and design the future experience strategy for the customer journey, ensuring that we're delivering value to users & the business.



Qrious NZ

Lead UX Design – Contract Jun 2019 - Jul 2019 (2 weeks) I led a project with Qrious for one of their clients – Transpower, setting a product & experience design direction to build a consolidated & seamless experience for their systems and conducting stakeholder workshops for a collaborative outcome.



Spark NZ

Chapter Lead, UX Designer Nov 2015 - Jun 2019 (3.8 years) As the design chapter lead, I work collaboratively with key stakeholders & designers to align designs with the product vision, creating measurable experiences & solutions that meet business goals. Working within our user-centred framework, I support teams to challenge creative thinking & seek innovative solutions to problems.

I also manage, mentor & supervise the design team on several project initiatives. Ensuring that all designs are executed at the highest quality, considering industry standards & customer needs.

One of my key projects was leading the design and build of Spark's design system, Spark Experience Toolkit (SET), which included defining components and the digital style guide. I was also acting as a guardian for SET, ensuring the quality, reusability, consistency of the experiences.



Hewlett Packard Singapore

Interaction Designer Jun 2011 - Oct 2015 (4.5 years) My role at HP was to interpret business needs into effective design solutions, mainly for the printers.

I was responsible for redefining & aligning the UI direction for printer operating systems across different business segments, including consumer, small business, & enterprise. These ranged across various touchscreen sizes, including both coloured & black & white interface.

As an Interaction Designer, I worked through the design process, from identifying user needs to conceptualising, creating design vision, workflows, interaction guidelines (UI architecture, patterns & behaviours) & UI prototypes. We regularly conducted the concept & usability testing to validate solutions.



Yahoo India

Visual & Interaction Designer Jan 2010 - Jun 2011 (1.6 years) My responsibilities included analysing online content browsing trends & anticipating/proposing future Yahoo products on various platforms, including mobile/tablets, web & software applications.

I worked closely with the business team for requirements to create concepts, wireframes, visual mockups.



Freelance

Design Consultant Feb 2009 - Nov 2009 (10 months) Working as a design consultant allowed me to work on multidisciplinary design projects (like interior designing, identity design & more), which included not just designing but execution and management. It was a competitive experience altogether, which helped me acquire the potentials of an individual professional designer.